<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Not Lost</title>
    <link>http://notlost.co</link>
    <pubDate>Wed, 24 Feb 2016 12:37:12 -0800</pubDate>
    
    <item>
      <title>Evidence of early medieval Muslim graves found in France</title>
      <link>http://notlost.co/today/evidence-of-early-medieval-muslim-graves-found-in-france</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Feb 2016 11:53:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <author>Kyle Roderick</author>
      <guid>http://notlost.co/today/evidence-of-early-medieval-muslim-graves-found-in-france</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Archaeological and genetic analysis may indicate that three skeletons buried in medieval graves in France may have been Muslim, according to a study published February 24, 2016 in the open-access journal PLOS ONE by Yves Gleize from the French National Institute for Preventive Archaeological Research (Inrap) and University of Bordeaux, France, Fanny Mendisco from University of Bordeaux, France, and colleagues.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Conservatives prefer using nouns, new research finds</title>
      <link>http://notlost.co/today/conservatives-prefer-using-nouns-new-research-finds</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Feb 2016 11:53:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <author>Kyle Roderick</author>
      <guid>http://notlost.co/today/conservatives-prefer-using-nouns-new-research-finds</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Conservatives prefer using nouns, new transatlantic research suggests. The research also established that conservatives generally, to a greater degree than liberals, tend to refer to things by their names, rather than describing them in terms of their features. An example would be saying someone &amp;lsquo;is an optimist&amp;rsquo;, rather than &amp;lsquo;is optimistic&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Astronomers Finally Pinpoint the Location of Mysterious Radio Bursts in Space</title>
      <link>http://notlost.co/today/astronomers-finally-pinpoint-the-location-of-mysterious-radio-bursts-in-space</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Feb 2016 11:53:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <author>Kyle Roderick</author>
      <guid>http://notlost.co/today/astronomers-finally-pinpoint-the-location-of-mysterious-radio-bursts-in-space</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;FRBs or “fast radio bursts” are extremely energetic pulses that only last for a few milliseconds. They’ve only been observed 17 times from random points in the sky. Now, a report in &lt;strong&gt;Nature&lt;/strong&gt;  shows that astronomers have been able to pinpoint the location of one that released two days worth of our Sun’s energy in a fraction of a second.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cardiologists use 3-D printing to personalize treatment for heart disease -- ScienceDaily</title>
      <link>http://notlost.co/today/cardiologists-use-3-d-printing-to-personalize-treatment-for-heart-disease-sciencedaily</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Feb 2016 11:53:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <author>Kyle Roderick</author>
      <guid>http://notlost.co/today/cardiologists-use-3-d-printing-to-personalize-treatment-for-heart-disease-sciencedaily</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Supercomputers are being used by clinicians to create 3-D models from patients with heart disease, with photos from a camera thinner than a human hair.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wild gorillas compose happy songs that they hum during meals | New Scientist</title>
      <link>http://notlost.co/today/wild-gorillas-compose-happy-songs-that-they-hum-during-meals-new-scientist</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Feb 2016 11:53:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <author>Kyle Roderick</author>
      <guid>http://notlost.co/today/wild-gorillas-compose-happy-songs-that-they-hum-during-meals-new-scientist</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Gorillas sing and hum when eating, a discovery that could help shed light on how language evolved in early humans. Singing seems to be a way for gorillas to express contentment with their meal, as well as for the head of the family to communicate to others that it is dinner time.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>One-Year Crew Returns from Space Station March 1; Live Coverage on NASA TV</title>
      <link>http://notlost.co/today/one-year-crew-returns-from-space-station-march-1-live-coverage-on-nasa-tv</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Feb 2016 11:53:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <author>Kyle Roderick</author>
      <guid>http://notlost.co/today/one-year-crew-returns-from-space-station-march-1-live-coverage-on-nasa-tv</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t miss it: NASA Television will provide complete coverage Tuesday, March 1, as three crew members depart the International Space Station, including NASA astronaut Scott Kelly and cosmonaut Mikhail Kornienko of the Russian space agency Roscosmos – the station’s first one-year crew.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Human survivors of Ebola may offer clue to effective treatment</title>
      <link>http://notlost.co/today/human-survivors-of-ebola-may-offer-clue-to-effective-treatment</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Feb 2016 11:38:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <author>Kyle Roderick</author>
      <guid>http://notlost.co/today/human-survivors-of-ebola-may-offer-clue-to-effective-treatment</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Human survivors of the Ebola might be the key to creating an effective therapy for those infected with the disease. A new study published in &lt;strong&gt;Science&lt;/strong&gt; shows how antibodies target part of a protein on the surface of the Ebola virus and treating the infection in mice.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FeedPress is Analytics and Podcast Hosting</title>
      <link>http://notlost.co/today/feedpress-is-analytics-and-podcast-hosting</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2016 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <author>Kyle Roderick</author>
      <guid>http://notlost.co/today/feedpress-is-analytics-and-podcast-hosting</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hosting and feed support provided by Feed.Press. &lt;a href=&quot;http://feed.press/morningshow&quot;&gt;Sign-up today&lt;/a&gt; and try FeedPress on a 14 day trial (no contracts or commitments). Use promo code &lt;code&gt;morningshow&lt;/code&gt; during checkout to get 10% off your first year.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Researchers develop new nanoparticle with potential to treat ocular cancer</title>
      <link>http://notlost.co/today/researchers-develop-new-nanoparticle-with-potential-to-treat-ocular-cancer</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2016 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <author>Kyle Roderick</author>
      <guid>http://notlost.co/today/researchers-develop-new-nanoparticle-with-potential-to-treat-ocular-cancer</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Researchers at the University of Michigan Kellogg Eye Center have developed a new nanoparticle that uses a tumor cell&amp;rsquo;s protective mechanism against itself—short-circuiting tumor cell metabolism and killing tumor cells.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>President Obama honors early career scientists with top White House award</title>
      <link>http://notlost.co/today/president-obama-honors-early-career-scientists-with-top-white-house-award</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2016 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <author>Kyle Roderick</author>
      <guid>http://notlost.co/today/president-obama-honors-early-career-scientists-with-top-white-house-award</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;President Obama has named the 106 recipients of the Presidential Early Career Award for Scientists and Engineers; the highest award for scientists and engineers in the early stages of their research career. The award recipients come from universities around the country and study subjects including biology, computer and information science, education and human resources, engineering, and more&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NASA Scientists, Engineers Receive Presidential Early Career Awards</title>
      <link>http://notlost.co/today/nasa-scientists-engineers-receive-presidential-early-career-awards</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2016 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <author>Kyle Roderick</author>
      <guid>http://notlost.co/today/nasa-scientists-engineers-receive-presidential-early-career-awards</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;President Obama Thursday named six NASA researchers as recipients of the 2016 Presidential Early Career Award for Scientists and Engineers (PECASE). These recipients, and 100 other federal researchers, will receive their awards in a ceremony later this year in Washington.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Chocolate Looks Like When Viewed Under a Scanning Electron Microscope</title>
      <link>http://notlost.co/today/what-chocolate-looks-like-when-viewed-under-a-scanning-electron-microscope</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Feb 2016 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <author>Kyle Roderick</author>
      <guid>http://notlost.co/today/what-chocolate-looks-like-when-viewed-under-a-scanning-electron-microscope</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Graduate student Jennifer Dailey talks about a class she has been teaching at Johns Hopkins University that focuses on the subject of chocolate, what it consists of, its various melting points and even what it looks like under a scanning electron microscope.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Functional biomarker for age-related macular degeneration found</title>
      <link>http://notlost.co/today/functional-biomarker-for-age-related-macular-degeneration-found</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Feb 2016 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <author>Kyle Roderick</author>
      <guid>http://notlost.co/today/functional-biomarker-for-age-related-macular-degeneration-found</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A new study has found adults whose eyes are slow to adjust to the dark have a greater risk of developing age-related macular degeneration; blurring of the center of vision.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cambits, a modular imaging system that can transform into many different cameras</title>
      <link>http://notlost.co/today/cambits-a-modular-imaging-system-that-can-transform-into-many-different-cameras</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Feb 2016 10:32:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <author>Kyle Roderick</author>
      <guid>http://notlost.co/today/cambits-a-modular-imaging-system-that-can-transform-into-many-different-cameras</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Cambits, a modular imaging system that can transform into many different cameras, developed by Columbia Engineering Computer Science Professor Shree Nayar and Makoto Odamaki, visiting scientist from Ricoh Corporation.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Putting Pluto’s Geology on the Map</title>
      <link>http://notlost.co/today/putting-plutos-geology-on-the-map</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Feb 2016 10:18:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <author>Kyle Roderick</author>
      <guid>http://notlost.co/today/putting-plutos-geology-on-the-map</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Nam ac velit faucibus, aliquet magna in, molestie elit. Praesent placerat, tellus vitae porttitor dictum, est odio interdum risus, non fermentum metus arcu ut sem. Aliquam tempor velit tortor, eget luctus diam hendrerit sit amet. Nam gravida arcu eu ullamcorper mollis. Morbi luctus et orci eget imperdiet. Ut consequat leo a justo lobortis, nec feugiat risus dignissim.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mauris eleifend, sem interdum dapibus.</title>
      <link>http://notlost.co/today/mauris-eleifend-sem-interdum-dapibus</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Feb 2016 22:09:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <author>Kyle Roderick</author>
      <guid>http://notlost.co/today/mauris-eleifend-sem-interdum-dapibus</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Integer vitae ex id nunc commodo consequat at quis odio. Aliquam quis ligula metus. Vivamus.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quisque imperdiet quam erat. Maecenas tincidunt orci iaculis fermentum</title>
      <link>http://notlost.co/today/quisque-imperdiet-quam-erat-maecenas-tincidunt-orci-iaculis-fermentum</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Feb 2016 21:11:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <author>Kyle Roderick</author>
      <guid>http://notlost.co/today/quisque-imperdiet-quam-erat-maecenas-tincidunt-orci-iaculis-fermentum</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Integer eleifend tortor eu orci dapibus, et lacinia nulla lacinia. Ut nunc lacus, condimentum eget augue non, venenatis euismod turpis. Mauris faucibus egestas nulla, a maximus orci interdum a.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Donec sagittis lorem vitae est</title>
      <link>http://notlost.co/today/donec-sagittis-lorem-vitae-est</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Feb 2016 20:20:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <author>Kyle Roderick</author>
      <guid>http://notlost.co/today/donec-sagittis-lorem-vitae-est</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In purus elit, rutrum ut justo a, lobortis congue augue. Vestibulum vitae ultricies mauris. Morbi vestibulum tortor ac arcu sodales dictum. Cras a bibendum dui.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Morbi bibendum quam sit amet.</title>
      <link>http://notlost.co/today/morbi-bibendum-quam-sit-amet</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Feb 2016 22:13:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <author>Kyle Roderick</author>
      <guid>http://notlost.co/today/morbi-bibendum-quam-sit-amet</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Cum sociis natoque penatibus et magnis dis parturient montes, nascetur ridiculus mus. Vestibulum posuere rutrum sodales. Nunc id volutpat enim, quis tincidunt est. Ut dictum interdum ante, vel luctus sem ullamcorper ut. Proin ut blandit diam. Integer id est nec orci placerat ullamcorper sed molestie nulla. Morbi ornare nisi non hendrerit cursus.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
