<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Nanowire</title>
    <link>http://notlost.co</link>
    <pubDate>Wed, 24 Feb 2016 22:18:21 -0800</pubDate>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Chocolate Looks Like When Viewed Under a Scanning Electron Microscope</title>
      <link>http://notlost.co/today/what-chocolate-looks-like-when-viewed-under-a-scanning-electron-microscope</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Feb 2016 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <author>Kyle Roderick</author>
      <guid>http://notlost.co/today/what-chocolate-looks-like-when-viewed-under-a-scanning-electron-microscope</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Graduate student Jennifer Dailey talks about a class she has been teaching at Johns Hopkins University that focuses on the subject of chocolate, what it consists of, its various melting points and even what it looks like under a scanning electron microscope.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Innovative device traces chemicals affecting human and environmental health</title>
      <link>http://notlost.co/today/innovative-device-traces-chemicals-affecting-human-and-environmental-health</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Feb 2016 12:08:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <author>Kyle Roderick</author>
      <guid>http://notlost.co/today/innovative-device-traces-chemicals-affecting-human-and-environmental-health</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The die off of honeybees may be linked to a group of halogenated chemicals that have recently been identified as an environmental contaminant. These chemicals are the focus of a study that analyzed soil and water samples and observed how these potentially hazardous chemicals can be absorbed by organisms.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Can gaming mend damaged brains?</title>
      <link>http://notlost.co/today/can-gaming-mend-damaged-brains</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Feb 2016 12:08:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <author>Kyle Roderick</author>
      <guid>http://notlost.co/today/can-gaming-mend-damaged-brains</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;First person shooter computer games, such as Medal of Honor, can help rehabilitate patients with Traumatic Brain Injuries, suggests new research.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Computers can tell if you&#39;re bored, shows new study</title>
      <link>http://notlost.co/today/computers-can-tell-if-youre-bored-shows-new-study</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Feb 2016 12:08:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <author>Kyle Roderick</author>
      <guid>http://notlost.co/today/computers-can-tell-if-youre-bored-shows-new-study</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Computers are able to read a person&amp;rsquo;s body language to tell whether they are bored or interested in what they see on the screen. The research shows that by measuring a person&amp;rsquo;s movements as they use a computer, it is possible to judge their level of interest by monitoring whether they display the tiny movements that people usually constantly exhibit, known as non-instrumental movements.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Conservatives prefer using nouns, new research finds</title>
      <link>http://notlost.co/today/conservatives-prefer-using-nouns-new-research-finds</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Feb 2016 11:53:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <author>Kyle Roderick</author>
      <guid>http://notlost.co/today/conservatives-prefer-using-nouns-new-research-finds</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Conservatives prefer using nouns, new transatlantic research suggests. The research also established that conservatives generally, to a greater degree than liberals, tend to refer to things by their names, rather than describing them in terms of their features. An example would be saying someone &amp;lsquo;is an optimist&amp;rsquo;, rather than &amp;lsquo;is optimistic&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Astronomers Finally Pinpoint the Location of Mysterious Radio Bursts in Space</title>
      <link>http://notlost.co/today/astronomers-finally-pinpoint-the-location-of-mysterious-radio-bursts-in-space</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Feb 2016 11:53:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <author>Kyle Roderick</author>
      <guid>http://notlost.co/today/astronomers-finally-pinpoint-the-location-of-mysterious-radio-bursts-in-space</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;FRBs or “fast radio bursts” are extremely energetic pulses that only last for a few milliseconds. They’ve only been observed 17 times from random points in the sky. Now, a report in &lt;strong&gt;Nature&lt;/strong&gt;  shows that astronomers have been able to pinpoint the location of one that released two days worth of our Sun’s energy in a fraction of a second.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cardiologists use 3-D printing to personalize treatment for heart disease -- ScienceDaily</title>
      <link>http://notlost.co/today/cardiologists-use-3-d-printing-to-personalize-treatment-for-heart-disease-sciencedaily</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Feb 2016 11:53:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <author>Kyle Roderick</author>
      <guid>http://notlost.co/today/cardiologists-use-3-d-printing-to-personalize-treatment-for-heart-disease-sciencedaily</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Supercomputers are being used by clinicians to create 3-D models from patients with heart disease, with photos from a camera thinner than a human hair.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wild gorillas compose happy songs that they hum during meals</title>
      <link>http://notlost.co/today/wild-gorillas-compose-happy-songs-that-they-hum-during-meals</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Feb 2016 11:53:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <author>Kyle Roderick</author>
      <guid>http://notlost.co/today/wild-gorillas-compose-happy-songs-that-they-hum-during-meals</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Gorillas sing and hum when eating, a discovery that could help shed light on how language evolved in early humans. Singing seems to be a way for gorillas to express contentment with their meal, as well as for the head of the family to communicate to others that it is dinner time.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>One-Year Crew Returns from Space Station March 1; Live Coverage on NASA TV</title>
      <link>http://notlost.co/today/one-year-crew-returns-from-space-station-march-1-live-coverage-on-nasa-tv</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Feb 2016 11:53:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <author>Kyle Roderick</author>
      <guid>http://notlost.co/today/one-year-crew-returns-from-space-station-march-1-live-coverage-on-nasa-tv</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t miss it: NASA Television will provide complete coverage Tuesday, March 1, as three crew members depart the International Space Station, including NASA astronaut Scott Kelly and cosmonaut Mikhail Kornienko of the Russian space agency Roscosmos – the station’s first one-year crew.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nanowire News on Twitter</title>
      <link>http://notlost.co/today/nanowire-news-on-twitter</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Feb 2016 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <author>Kyle Roderick</author>
      <guid>http://notlost.co/today/nanowire-news-on-twitter</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Nanowire News is a quick, daily, curated list of interesting science news. Follow along on Twitter to know when the latest links and summaries have been posted each day.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Human survivors of Ebola may offer clue to effective treatment</title>
      <link>http://notlost.co/today/human-survivors-of-ebola-may-offer-clue-to-effective-treatment</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Feb 2016 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <author>Kyle Roderick</author>
      <guid>http://notlost.co/today/human-survivors-of-ebola-may-offer-clue-to-effective-treatment</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Human survivors of the Ebola might be the key to treating those infected with the disease. A new study published in &lt;strong&gt;Science&lt;/strong&gt; shows how antibodies target part of a protein on the surface of the Ebola virus and treating the infection in mice.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
